Welcome to Deep Reinforcement Learning.
欢迎学习深度强化学习课程
Interest in the field of reinforcement learning seems to have almost exploded
随着 AlphaGo 等成功故事和 OpenAI 等平台的出现
with success stories like AlphaGo and platforms like OpenAI.
强化学习领域忽然间吸引了无数人的关注
Research in this area has been moving at a steady pace since the 1980s,
对该领域的研究自上世纪 80 年代起呈稳步发展状态
but it has really taken off with recent advances in deep learning.
但是随着近期深度学习的发展 强化学习也飞速得到发展
As we progress through this module,
在我们学习这一单元的过程中
you will design intelligent agents that can learn to carry out complex control tasks.
你将设计能够执行复杂控制任务的智能体
These include simple domains like physics problems and board games to
包括物理问题等简单的领域和棋类游戏
video games where the agent processes raw pixel data and even robotics.
以及智能体会处理原始像素数据的视频游戏 甚至包括机器人
My favorite part of reinforcement learning is watching
对于强化学习 我最喜欢的一个方面是
an agent grow and get better and better at a task.
观察智能体不断成长并越来越擅长于某个任务
This is not always easy to achieve but
这一点并不始终容易实现
once you can get your agent to learn the nuances of a task,
但是一旦让智能体学会任务的各个细节部分
it can perform it flawlessly from then on.
它就可以完美地执行该任务
And that is the most rewarding experience in the world.
这是世界上最有成就感的体验
Before we dive into "Deep Reinforcement Learning",
在学习深度强化学习课程之前
let's quickly review some fundamental concepts.
我们来快速复习下一些基本概念
Reinforcement learning problems are typically framed
强化学习问题通常都会转化为
as Markov Decision Processes or MDPs.
马尔可夫决策流程 简称 MDP
An MDP consists of a set of states S and actions A along with probabilities P,
一个 MDP 由一组状态 S 动作 A 概率 P
rewards R and a discount factor gamma.
奖励 R 和折扣因子 γ 组成
P captures how frequently different transitions and rewards occur,
P 表示不同转换和奖励的发生频率
often modeled as a single joint probability where the state and
通常建模为单个联合概率
reward at any time step t plus one depend only on the state
任何时间步 t+1 的状态和奖励仅依赖于
and action taken at the previous time step t.
在上个时间步 t 的状态和采取的动作
This characteristic of certain environments is known as the Markov property.
特定环境的这一特性称之为马尔可夫性
There are two quantities that we are typically interested in.
我们通常对两个量感兴趣
The value of a state V(S),
我们尝试估算或预测的
which we try to estimate or predict.
状态值 V(S)
And the value of an action taken in a certain state,
以及在特定状态下采取的动作的值 Q(S,A)
Q(S, A) which can help us decide what action to take.
后者可以帮助我们判断应采取什么样的动作
These two mappings or functions are very much interrelated and help us find
这两个映射或方法关系非常紧密
an optimal policy for our problem pie star that maximizes the total reward received.
可以帮助我们找到问题的最优策略 π* 从而最大化接收的总奖励
Note that since MDPs are probabilistic in nature,
注意 因为 MDP 本质上具有概率性
we can't predict with complete certainty
因此我们无法完全确定地预测
what future rewards we will get and for how long.
未来将获得什么样的奖励以及持续多久
So, we typically aim for total expected reward.
因此我们通常计算的是总预期奖励
This is where the discount factor gamma comes into play as well.
这时候就要提到折扣因子 γ 了
It is used to assign a lower weighted to
在计算状态和动作值时
future rewards when computing state and action values.
我们用它来为未来的奖励分配更低的权重
Reinforcement learning algorithms are generally classified into two groups.
强化学习算法通常分为两大类别
Model-based approaches such as policy iteration and
基于模型的方法 例如策略迭代
value iteration require a known transition and reward model.
以及需要已知转换和奖励模型的值迭代
They essentially apply dynamic programming to iteratively compute
它们本质上通过动态规划并使用该模型
the desired value functions and optimal policies using that model.
以迭代方式计算期望的值函数和最优策略
On the other hand, model-free approaches including
另一方面 蒙特卡洛方法和时间差分学习等
Monte Carlo Methods and Temporal-Difference Learning don't require an explicit model.
不基于模型的方法不需要明确的模型
They sample the environment by carrying out exploratory actions and
它们通过执行探索性动作对环境抽样
use the experience gained to directly estimate value functions.
并使用获得的经验直接估计值函数
Okay, obviously there is more to it but that's reinforcement learning in a nutshell.
这就是强化学习的简单介绍 当然还有更多内容
Deep Reinforcement Learning is
深度强化学习是一个相对较新的术语
a relatively recent term that refers to approaches that use deep learning,
是指使用深度学习（主要是多层神经网络）
mainly, Multi-Layer Neural Networks to solve reinforcement learning problems.
解决强化学习问题的方法
Now, reinforcement learning is typically characterized by finite MDPs,
强化学习通常包含有限的 MDP
where the number of states and actions is limited.
即状态和动作数量是有限的
But there are so many problems where the space of states and actions is very
但是有太多的问题具有非常大的状态和动作空间
large or even made of continuous real value numbers.
甚至由连续的实数组成
Traditional algorithms use a table or
传统算法使用表格或字典
a dictionary or other finite structure to capture state and action values.
或其他有限结构来记录状态和动作值
They no longer work for such problems.
但是不再适合此类问题
So, the first thing you will learn in this module is how to
因此 你在这一单元内首先将学习的是
generalize these algorithms to work with large and continuous spaces.
如何泛化这些算法以便适合大型连续空间
That lays the foundation for developing Deep Reinforcement Learning algorithms including
这就为开发深度强化学习算法奠定了基础
value-based techniques like Deep Q-Learning
包括深度 Q 学习等基于值的技巧
and those that directly try to optimize the policy,
以及直接尝试优化策略的方法
such as Policy Gradients.
例如策略梯度
Finally, you will look at more advanced approaches that try to
最后 你将了解尝试结合这两类方法的更高级方法
combine the best of both worlds, Actor-Critic Methods.
即行动者-评论者方法
These algorithms can be hard to understand.
这些算法可能比较难懂
So, don't worry if you find them challenging at first.
如果你一开始觉得有挑战性 也别担心
Make sure you practice implementing the core competence
确保练习实现这些算法的核心部分
of these algorithms and apply them to various environments.
并将它们应用到各种环境中
Observe how they perform.
观察它们的性能
That is the only way to master Deep Reinforcement Learning.
这是掌握深度强化学习的唯一方式